<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker on Christoph Hartmann</title>
    <link>https://lollyrock.com/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker on Christoph Hartmann</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://lollyrock.com/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>InSpec for Docker</title>
      <link>https://lollyrock.com/posts/inspec-for-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lollyrock.com/posts/inspec-for-docker/</guid>
      <description>Docker environments enable you to manage fast-moving infrastructure. The faster you move, the better your test environment needs to be. InSpec provides that capability. With the recent addition of 3 new resources: docker, docker_image and a docker_container, it became even easier to verify docker hosts and docker containers. This blog post demonstrates how to use InSpec to verify your Docker environments.
Overview   Docker Architecture Overview  Before I am talking about docker infrastructure testing, I need to explain the different parts of the docker universe quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Execute commands in a Docker sandbox</title>
      <link>https://lollyrock.com/posts/execute-in-docker-sandbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lollyrock.com/posts/execute-in-docker-sandbox/</guid>
      <description>If we deal a lot with data from an untrusted source, we want to operate on data in a sandbox. For example, every file we handle may includes a virus and tries to attack our machine.
Docker is an amazing tool to run arbitrary commands inside a sandbox. It is useful for testing applications or building complete application images as offered by Docker Hub.
To address the use case, it is required to build containers on demand and mix them with pre-known commands (which typically fit in a Dockerfile) and custom user defined commands.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>